Hmm? Surprisingly stable.
嗯？稳定得不可思议
Hey Ratchet, is that Synthetic Energon?
嘿 救护车 那是人造能量吗？
Well, yes.
嗯 是的
In fact I'm preparing to test the sample.
实际上我正准备测试这些样本
I see that you come equipped with protective goggles.
看来你戴了护目镜
I can watch?
我可以看了？
Haha, We just add some to the test engine.
哈哈 只需要往测试引擎中注入一些
It works! Bee!
起作用了！小蜂！
Dah, dah dah?
等一下 等一下
This iteration of the formula requires further trial
在我们考虑将它用来制造燃料
before we could even think about using it for fuel
弹药 或是急救品之前
ammunition or first aid
这个配方样本需要进一步的实验
which is rather unfortunate since our own reserves are in all time low.
很不幸 因为我们的能量储备一向不足
Our severely outnumbered warriors have been rapidly burdening through our stockpile of late
敌众我寡 我们的战士为了对付霸天虎而疲于奔命 迅速地消耗着能量储备
as the Decepticon army continues to run us and ground us down.
造成了霸天虎始终在较量中占据上风
Natural Energon is in such short supply on your planet,
天然能量在你们的星球上十分稀缺
and Megatron seems to have his oily claws buried deep in all the earth deposits.
而且看起来威震天的脏手已经遍布地球
But, if we can successfully produce a synthetic form
但是 如果我们能成功制造出人造能量
we can manufacture all the energy we'll ever need.
就能解决所有的能源需求问题
Raw Energon on the move.
有移动的能量矿石信号
Again.
又来了
Their recent activity suggests a familiar pattern.
最近的动向表明 他们又重操旧业了
The Decepticons are desperately scouting for new deposits to mine.
霸天虎们急于探测出新的能量矿
Autobots...
汽车人…
Optimus, if one of you comes back wounded this time, well...
擎天柱 如果你们这次回来的时候有人受伤的话 那个
our Energon reserves are nearly depleted.
我们能量储备已经几乎耗尽了
Understood.
我懂了
Activate the Ground Bridge.
启动环陆桥
Autobots, roll out.
汽车人 出发
Sometimes, I wish I could do more.
有时候我真希望自己能派上用场
Ratchet, wake up!
救护车 醒一醒！
Ugh?
呃？
How is it that such small beings can be so loud.
你人不大 嗓门倒是不小啊？
Are you hurt? You fell.
你受伤了吗？你摔倒了
I'm fine. I'm...
我很好 我…
more than fine.
…好得不得了
Hah, energy efficiency is of thirty percent?
哈 能量效率提升了三成？
Motor functions optimal?
马达功能处于最佳状态？
Any word from the others?
其他人那儿有什么消息吗？
Knock Out, can't we just Bridge out of here?
击倒 我们就不能直接传送走人吗？
This cube is putting some serious drag on me.
这个方块背起来很重
The more we give the Autobots a work out
我们给汽车人制造的麻烦越多
the more fuel they burn.
他们消耗的能量就越多
And we win the Energon race.
然后我们就能赢得这场能量竞赛
Besides, here comes air support.
何况 空中支援来了
Arcee, fall back, you are out-numbered!
阿尔茜 后撤 他们人太多了！
We are always out-numbered.
我们向来都是以寡敌众
We need that Energon!
我们需要那个能量！
Ratchet, lock on to Arcee's coordinates,
救护车 锁定阿尔茜的坐标
and prepare an emergency Ground Bridge.
准备紧急传送
I'm locked up.
我锁定了
Arcee, decelerate and prepare to return to base.
阿尔茜 减速 准备返回基地
Save it, Ratchet, I'm too close.
省省吧 救护车 我和对方靠得太近了
Don't be a fool!
别做傻事！
She's hurt.
她受伤了
Man the Ground Bridge.
操纵环陆桥
HOOAAH!
呼呀！！
Ratchet?
救护车？
Looks like the Autobots brought in a ringer.
看来汽车人来了个开外挂的
Well then I'll ring his bell.
那我们就让他现形吧
You'll have to wait.
你得等下次了
HOOAAH!
呼呀！
What happened?
发生了什么？
I only saw the glory aftermath,
我只看到辉煌的战果
but I hear the doc was on one Bot ragging machine.
但听起来医生上演了一出单骑破敌的好戏
Whoa...
哇！
Oh, hey, little fella.
噢 嘿 小家伙
Alright, what's you secret.
好吧 你的秘密是什么？
No secret,
没什么秘密
just a thing something I like to call Synthen.
只是一种我喜欢称它为“合能”的东西
From the data Bulkhead transcribed?
按照隔板记录下来的那些数据合成出来的？
I thought the formula was...
我以为方程式是…
Incomplete? Hehe, not anymore.
…不完整的？呵呵 不再是了
So Ratchet makes a better tough guy than I do a smart guy?
救护车作为猛男要远胜我的聪明才智？
Ratchet, I question the wisdom of using yourself as a test subject.
救护车 我质疑你用自己做试验是否明智
Optimus, you didn't see Ratchet out there.
擎天柱 你没看到救护车当时的表现
He was an overdrive.
简直是大暴发啊
We should all try this stuff.
我们都应该试试这个
Or give Ratchet more so we can take a vacation.
或者让救护车多喝点 然后我们就能放个假了
I agree that the initial results seem promising,
我承认初期的效果颇为令人期待
but I recommend that further testing be confined to machines,
但我建议在机器上做进一步的测试
not Autobots.
而不是在汽车人身上
Out-numbered, though, we may be, old friend.
虽然现在是敌众我寡 老朋友
We need a warrior in the laboratory right now,
但比起战场上的战士
more than we need another in the field.
我们现在更需要的是实验室里的战士
And then, he came right at me, and I...
然后 他直接朝我扑过来 于是我
well, come on, Bulk, come at me.
嗯… 来 小隔 过来打我
I don't want to hurt you, Ratch.
我可不想伤到你 老救
I said, come at me!
我说 打我！
HOOAAH!
呼呀！
What was that?
那是怎么回事？
You have competition, Bulk.
你有竞争对手了 小隔
I'm a bit stronger than I used to be.
我比之前要强壮一些
Also a bit fast, hehaha...
速度也快了一点 嘿嘿嘿
Say you could take me, muscle car?
要跟我较量下吗 肌肉车？
Wimp. How¡¯s it hummin?
胆小鬼 感觉怎么样？
Did he just?
他是不是有些…
Stronger, faster, studlier.
更强 更快 更流氓了
I need to be at the top of my game.
我要始终保持最佳状态
Our survival depends upon it.
这关乎我们的生死存亡
Looks like the Cons hit another vein.
看起来虎子们又找到了一个矿脉
Autobots, roll out.
汽车人 出发
Heyhey, shouldn't we wait for our secret weapon?
嘿 嘿 我们不应该等等我们的秘密武器吗？
This mission is unlikely to require medical expertise.
这次任务不需要医疗专家
But you'll never know if you may require additional fire power.
但万一你需要额外的火力支援呢？
Bumblebee can handle Ground Bridge duty.
大黄蜂可以操作环陆桥
Time to put some hurt on those Decepticons.
是时候去痛打一顿那些霸天虎了
The signal is weak.
信号很微弱
They may have hit a vein
他们就算找到一个矿脉
but they won't find much of Energon pulse
也找不到多少能量
not here.
起码这里没戏
I take some comfort in the fact that Megatron seems as
威震天像我们一样急于找到能量
desperate to find the stuff as we are.
这个事实倒令人宽慰
Do you two always talk this mush during these missions?
你们两个在任务中总是这么废话连篇吗？
Autobots!
汽车人！
It's alright.
没事了
I'm an emergency vehicle.
我是一辆救护车
Why the big rush?
干吗这么急？
Just trying to get as far as I can from the Autobot stink.
我只是想离汽车人臭虫远点
Does your boss know you have a potty mouth?
你的老大知道你有一张臭嘴吗？
Maybe I should pay him a visit and tell him.
也许我该拜访他一下 顺便告诉他
Get melted, wheel-grinder.
你该进熔毁炉 死轮子
Melted? Now there is the concept.
熔毁？好提议
I won't ask you a second time--
我不会再问第二遍
where is Megatron?
威震天在哪儿？
No, no--Nooooo!!
不 不…不！！
That's all I know, really!
我知道的就这些了 真的！
Now was that so difficult?
敬酒不吃吃罚酒
Ratchet, what are you doing?
救护车 你在干什么？
Get results.
问口供
And breaking protocol.
也破坏了原则
That was a Decepticon minor, servant class.
那是个霸天虎仆从 劳工等级
Not warrior class.
不是战士级别的
Oh, let me guess: I'm just the medic.
哦 让我猜你要说什么：我只是个医疗兵
Autobots do not inflict harm unless all other options have been exhausted.
除非万不得已 汽车人从不伤害他人
It is what separates us from the Decepticons.
这就是我们和霸天虎之间的不同之处
Ha! Is this really the time for another lecture, Optimuse?
哈！现在是讲大道理的时候吗 擎天柱？
You didn't just happen to discover Megatron's current location, did you?
碰巧发现威震天所在位置的人不是你 对吧？
Well, I did.
而我做到了
And you happen to know where there is a stockpile of raw Energon right for the taking?
你知道哪里能找到大量的能量矿藏吗？
I do!
我知道！
Come on, Ratchet. Calm it down.
行了 救护车 冷静点
Calm is the last thing we need!
冷静这东西毫无是处！
Calm is what lost us Cybertron!
是冷静让我们失去了塞博特恩！
The Cons have a warship, an army,
虎子们有战舰 军队
all this Energon scouting.
频繁的能量探测活动
You think Megatron isn't gearing up for something big?
你不认为威震天在酝酿什么大动作吗？
We are squandering our resources
我们浪费了大量资源
chasing after his crumbs.
却只能捡他们的残渣剩饭
When we really should be hitting him hard
我们本应该去揍他们
and hitting him now...
现在就去揍他们
precisely where it hurts!
狠狠地戳到他们的痛处
A direct assault on the Decepticons would only provoke retaliation...
直接攻击霸天虎只会招来报复行为…
and lead to incalculable losses.
并且导致无法估算的损失
I will not endanger innocent human lifes.
我不会让无辜的人类也卷入危险
Yet you seem to have no problem endangering ours!
但你却不介意将我们卷入危险！
Just ask Cliffjumper!
问问飞过山吧！
Oh, I forgot!
噢 我忘记了！
He couldn't be here today!
他今天已经不可能出现在这里了！
That's it!
够了！
You know your problem, Optimus?
你知道你的问题吗 擎天柱？
For such a big, strong Bot...
你是个如此高大 如此强壮的汽车人
you're soft.
却如此…优柔寡断
You didn't pound Megatron into scrap when you had the chance!
你没有抓住机会把威震天砸成废铁！
Many chances, in fact!
错失了那么多良机！
I'm afraid that the Synthetic Energon has impaired you judgement, old friend.
恐怕人造能量影响了你的判断力 老朋友
I am confining you to base until further notice.
我命令你不得离开基地 直至接到新命令
Bumblebee, bridge us back.
大黄蜂 把我们传送回去
Fine...
好吧…
Ummmm! Yahhhh!
呼！呀！
Can't get a fix on Ratchet's coordinates.
无法定位救护车的坐标
That bogus Energon must be scrambling his signal.
那自负的人造能量一定搅乱了他的信号
Keep trying.
继续尝试
We've got to find Rathcet,
我们必须找到救护车
before he finds Megatron.
在他找到威震天之前
Yeah, she's kinda domineering and the extra arms are weird,
是 她是有点跋扈 多出来的手臂也很奇怪
but... I find myself intrigued by her.
但是…我发现自己对她还蛮来电的
I was wondering when you might show.
我还在想你什么时候会送上门来
You call yourself a scientist?
你还配叫科学家？
You were supported to have located a fresh Energon source by now.
你现在早该找到一处新的能量矿藏了！
Apologies, Lord Megatron.
我道歉 威震天陛下
We got little distracted by the new Autobot who attacked us.
一个新汽车人袭击了我们 我们有些分心
Really?
真的？
And what new Autobot would that be?
那个新汽车人是谁？
HOOAAH!
呼呀！
Well, the...
呃 那么…
That is your fiercesome new adversary?
这就是你所谓的新对手？
Hahahaha! He is Optimus Prime's mech.
哈哈哈哈哈 他是擎天柱的医疗兵
Oh, no, Megatron.
噢 不 威震天
I am your doctor of doom.
我是你的验尸官
HOOAAH!
呼呀！
Alright then.
那好吧
For Cybertron!
为了塞博特恩！
Ahhh, Ahhhhh!
啊啊 啊啊！
Ratchet is rather more spirited than I recollect.
救护车的确比我印象中的要生龙活虎一些
Chemical enhancement, perhaps?
也许是化学作用？
There is your laboratory sample, doctor.
给你个实验室样本 医生
Find out...
查明原因
If a chemical can do this for Optimus Prime's lab doc, hehe
如果一种化学药剂可以把擎天柱的医官变成这样 呵呵
imagine what it could do for our troops.
想想它对我们的军队所产生的影响吧
Oh, Optimus, I've been a fool.
噢 擎天柱 我可真傻
Optimus, Ratchet's signal.
擎天柱 有救护车的信号
It's back online.
它重新出现了
Bumblebee.
大黄蜂
Autobots, roll out.
汽车人 出发
Doctor, to doctor, I must say,
大家同为医官 我得说
you contribution to the Decepticon cause is very much appreciated.
感谢你对霸天虎作出的贡献
I'll be sure to boast of your accomplishment when you are gone.
我一定会在你死后为你歌功颂德的
Which will happen in three, two...
在我倒数之后会发生什么呢？三 二…
Scrap.
该死
Hahahahah... what are you going to do?
哈哈哈哈 你想干什么？
Drink it?
喝了它？
No. I'm going to destroy it.
不 我要毁了它
You idiot!
你这蠢货！
Megatron will have my head!
威震天会要了我的脑袋！
Easy, old friend.
放轻松 老朋友
You lost a lot of Energon--
你失去了很多能量…
good and bad.
喜忧参半
I... I didn't intended to hurt anyone.
我…我没想过要伤害任何人
I just... wanted so... badly to...
我只是…
Help us.
太想帮忙了
We know.
我们知道
But you nearly caused the loss of something irreplaceable--
但你差点造成了无可挽回的损失…
our medic,
我们的医官
and a most trusted friend.
还有一个值得信赖的朋友
You did lead us to a much needed Energon supply.
你的确带我们找到了急需的能量供给
And, for that,
为此
we should all be thankful.
大家都应该感谢你
The Synthetic Energon formula clearly needs refining before it can be tested again-
很显然 在再次测试之前 人造能量的配方需要进一步改进――
on machines, not Autobots.
然后通过机器测试 而不是汽车人
Let us take comfort in the fact that you
好在你当场销毁了残余的样本